(２人)ん
(３人)ん
(日向翔陽)お前何企んでる
そうはいかないぞ
What are you up to?!
I won't let you!
(田中)日向逃げすぎ
(西谷)翔陽
Hinata, you're acting too scared!
Shouyou, he's not up to anything!
これは企んでる顔じゃなくて
笑顔だぞたぶん
He's trying to smile! I think!
(東峰)
たぶんとか言うんじゃないよ西谷
I think it's rude, Nishinoya!
(影山飛雄)日向ぶ飛ばす
(澤村)おお
Hinata, you're dead meat!
Ooh!
≪あの影山が
笑顔を作る努力を
Our grumpy Kageyama is making the effort to smile.
(菅原･
((例のサインな作戦変更だ))
You know the signals we talked about? It's time to change our strategy.
あざす
ｻｲﾝのこと菅原さんに聞いたか
Thank you.
Did you hear about the signals from Sugawara?
セト間に聞いた
He told me between sets.
よしゃ
All right!
ガンガン行くぜ
おうよ
We're going hard and fast.
You got it!
(部員)行け
行け行け行け行け青城
Episode Twenty-two:
Evolution
(菅原)はぁ
(山口)ん
Hey, it's not that unusual.
(菅原)不思議そうな顔すんなよ
結構緊張したんだからな
That was really nerve-wracking.
Really?
(山口)そうなんですか
去年のインタハイまでは
当然３年生がいたから
Up till last year's interhigh, I didn't get to play in many official matches because third-years had seniority.
俺公式戦は
そんなに出てないんだよ
悔しいけど影山の方が
場数多く踏んでんじゃないかなぁ
I hate to say it, but Kageyama has more actual match experience.
(月島)の割にはだいぶ
テンパてましたけどね影山
For all his so-called experience, he sure got riled up.
でその王様
早速サブですけど
So anyway, His Majesty has to serve straight off.
大丈夫ですかね
(澤村)影山ナイサ
You think he can manage?
Give us a good serve, Kageyama!
Serve up a point!
(田中)ナイサ一本
ふ
(菅原)影山うれしそうだな
(山口)ですね
Kageyama looks happy.
Yeah.
なんか安心するわ
(山口)何がですか
That's a relief.
What do you mean?
(菅原)どんな選手でも
試合に出るときの
I was thinking that all of us seem to have the same sort of pride when we're put in a match.
誇らしさみたいなのは
同じなんだろうなて思てさ
天才だろうが凡人だろうが
Prodigies and Average Joes alike.
(武田)影山君リラクスですよ
Kageyama, remember to relax!
(武田)あ大丈夫ですね
(繋心)ん
I think he's okay.
(及川)う一本で切るよ
One point and he's gone!
(一同)おお
ピ
Yeah!
(岩泉)渡
おお
Watari!
(嶋田)サビスエス
(滝ノ上)リベロから取た
A service ace!
And they got it off the libero!
Karasuno                   Aoba Jousai
これで同点
しゃ
Now they're tied up!
Yes!
I'm sorry!
(渡)すいません
(岩泉)オｯケオｯケ次一本
Don't fret it. Let's get the next point!
Yay!
ウェイ
ん
え
Yay!
What?
ハイタチだバカ
パチン
Double high five, you dummy!
ウェイ
Yay!
(金田一)
影山がハイタチしてるぞ
Kageyama is doing double high fives.
(国見)おお
ピ
Yeah.
(岩泉)すまんカバ
はい
Sorry, cover it!
Right!
They're scattered!
崩した返てくるぞ
(花巻)く
It's coming back!
(西谷)チャンスボル
Here's our chance!
Send it?
(花巻)≪来い
(金田一)≪くれ
Give me?
Which?
(花巻･金田一)≪どち
(２人)≪何も言わない
He didn't say anything!
出た
あの速攻マジ意味分かんねぇ
There it is!
That fast attack is totally ridiculous!
Okay! Now Karasuno is in the lead!
(嶋田)よしこれで烏野逆転
Karasuno                   Aoba Jousai
((菅原さんて決めると
すげぇ褒めてくれるんだぜ))
When I make a ball count,
Sugawara showers me with compliments!
おい日向
ん
Hey, Hinata.
よくやた
上司か
Good work.
Who are you, my boss?
(菅原)くぅ日向
キレキレだなちくしょう
Now Hinata is in his element, dammit!
影山も水を得た魚て感じだな
And Kageyama is like a fish in water!
(月島)≪カゲヤマ≫
(山口)≪トビウオ≫
Kageyama?
A fish?
くそ
(及川)はい落ち着いて
Shit.
Okay, calm down.
焦てこちが
崩れてやる必要はないよ
There's no need to panic and
mess up our plays like they did.
一本取り返せば問題ない
はい
Once we take a point back, we're all good.
Yes, sir!
(岩泉)おいその顔とポズ
腹立つやめろ
Hey. Stop striking that pose.
It pisses me off.
You're mean!
ひどいな
ピ
Okay!
(岩泉)しゃ
(金田一)岩泉さんﾅｲｽﾚｼｰﾌﾞ
Iwaizumi, nice receive!
ピ
Has Kageyama gotten his rhythm back?
(入畑)≪影山
平常のリズムを取り戻したか≫
I'm sorry.
Shake it off!
≪いやそれだけじゃない
No, there's more to it.
相手のブロクばかり
気にしていたはずが
I should've made it closer to the sideline.
He devoted his full attention to the opponent blockers before,
Don't sweat it! Those were all good serves.
but now he's being slightly more attentive to his teammates as well.
ささやかながら仲間の方へも
意識が向くようになてきている≫
Thank you.
うん
ピ
(繋心)
≪よし出し惜しみすんなよ
Okay, don't start holding back!
このセトを取らなきゃ
どうしようもねぇ
We're screwed unless we take this set!
変人速攻ガンガン使てけ≫
Kunimi, give us a good one!
Make those deviant fast attacks hard and fast!
よしゃ
Okay!
ナイスレシブ
Nice receive!
≪影山は日向に｢俺がいれば
お前は最強だ｣て言たけど
Kageyama told Hinata that "as long as I'm around, you're the greatest,"
(菅原)≪お前だて
but it goes both ways.
(菅原)
≪日向との攻撃なら最強なんだ≫
Your and Hinata's combined attack
is the greatest.
(滝ノ上)よし
先に２０点台に乗た
Okay, we hit 20 points first!
Karasuno                   Aoba Jousai
Now we're in the final stretch.
(嶋田)さあ大詰めだぞ
パチン
ぎゃ
≪よし２０点台で
Okay, we've hit the 20 point mark.
That hurt!
It's for motivation!
Here's where the real challenge starts.
問題はこからかな
なんで
月島ｖｓ影山みたいになてんだ
Why is this turning into Tsukishima versus Kageyama?!
ピ
(田中)一本
One point!
Hinata, give us a good one!
(澤村)日向ナイサ
うわぁ
(花巻)ネトイン
It's over the net!
Here's our chance!
チャンスボル影山
(岩泉)松つんナイスカバ
Mattsun, nice cover!
Kageyama!
ピ
(烏野一同)しゃ
Yes!
トスは
(東峰)もうちょい高く頼む
How was the set?
A little higher, please.
はい
Yes, sir!
Karasuno                   Aoba Jousai
おさすがに青城もタイムか
Seijou had to call for a timeout sometime.
(松川)１０番が後ろに下がて
１１番が前衛に来ると
When number ten goes back and
number eleven comes to the front row,
烏野はｾﾝﾀｰ使う回数が減るよな
(及川)うん
Karasuno does less center attacks.
Yeah.
単純に飛雄はあのノポ君が
苦手なんじゃない
It could simply be that Tobio doesn't like the beanpole.
昨日の試合も今日も
Just like in yesterday's match, they don't seem to be communicating in today's match.
まともにコミュニケション
取てる感じじゃない
たぶん飛雄は
烏野のスパイカの中で
I think that among all of Karasuno's spikers,
Tobio finds the beanpole the hardest to work with.
いちばん
あのノポ君を上手に使えない
(松川)やぱ
お前とは友達になりたくねぇな
Now I know I never want to be friends with you.
(及川)なんで
(花巻)弱みとか握られそうじゃん
How come?!
You'd ferret out my weaknesses.
Why would I want to learn the weakness of a teammate?!
(及川)チムメイトの弱み握て
どうすんのさ
(縁下)((菅原さんてさ
スパイカそれぞれの表情とか
I think he talks to each spiker to read their faces and emotional states more
Tsukishima, I think you might be jumping to block too soon. Delay it more.
今日の調子とか
そういうのを見てるんだと思うよ))
and to get a bearing on how well they feel on a given day.
Understood.
Yamaguchi, keep yelling things out!
出しナイスな
(山口)はい
Right!
What?
(月島)何
≪表情を読むとか言われても
How am I supposed to read his face?
むかつく顔てこと以外
分かんねぇし≫
All I know is that his face pisses me off!
(菅原)影山まずは会話だ会話
Kageyama.
Start with a conversation.
特に月島には
真向コミュニケションだぞ
With a guy like Tsukishima,
you need direct communication.
はい
ピ
Yes, sir.
(澤村)オライ
I've got it!
う
拾た
カウンタ来るぞ
They retrieved it! Look out for the counter!
Nice receive!
なんか
いずそうな打ち方だな月島
Tsukishima seems to be having trouble hitting it.
く
They caught up to us!
追いつかれた
くそ同点か
Shit, we're tied!
(ユウコ)ブレイクだ
(ハルカ)ブレイクだね
They scored!
Yeah.
先生
はい
Sir!
Right!
(青城一同)よしゃ
All right!
(他校生)やぱ攻撃力不足か
Do they need a stronger offense?
烏野はこの場面で
１０番いないのはきついよなぁ
Karasuno has it rough without
their number ten in this situation.
おらおら顔強張てんぞ
Come on, guys!
You look too tense!
(田中)ぶ
(繋心)落ち着いて行け
Stay calm!
You're moving well!
動きはいいぞ
(田中)うす
Yessir.
おい
(２人)ん
Hey.
今のトスはどうでしたかこら
How was that last set for you? Eh?
(月島)なんで田中さん口調なの
(田中)なんですかこら
Why are you talking like Tanaka?
What's that? Eh?
｢黙てこのトスを打て庶民｣て
言われてるみたいで腹立つ
It pisses me off 'cause it's like being told,
"Shut up and hit it, you pleb."
ああ
≪また月島は言い方子供だな≫
Huh?!
There you go again, Tsukishima!
You're such a child!
≪言い争いしてる余裕は
ないんだよ≫
There's no time to bicker like that!
どういう意味だ
(３人)あ
What do you mean?
こちにもやり方があるから
I have my own way of doing things, so I want sets to be consistent.
トスは一定にしてほしい
あのどういう
たぶん影山は
Um, what's going on?
My best guess is that when Kageyama sets a quick attack for Tsukishima, he also signals where the ball should go.
月島にＡクイクを上げるとき
打つコスさえも
トスで指示を出している
Cross
トスの位置が
ボル１個セｯタ側ならクロス
A set near the setter means cross-court.
遠ければタンて感じで
Away from the setter means turn-swing.
Turn
影山は当然決まりやすいと
思た方に打たそうとしてる
Kageyama obviously places it where he thinks it would be easiest to hit.
でも月島はそれが打ちづらい
てことなんじゃねぇかな
However, Tsukishima probably
finds it hard to hit sets like that.
考えてるのは君だけじゃない
You're not the only one who's thinking about stuff.
相手の守備の形
自分が今日よく決まてる攻撃
Whether it's the opponent's defense formation or the attacks that work for us that day,
みんな何かしら考えてる
everyone is always thinking.
日向ですら
一応何か考えてるから
Even Hinata thinks occasionally.
普通の速攻を
使えるようになたんでしょ
That's how he learned how to do regular fast attacks.
辛うじてだけど
ですらてなんだ
Barely, anyway.
What do you mean, "even"?
What do you mean, "barely"?!
辛うじててなんだ
(菅原)まあまあ
There, there.
分かた
(月島)え
Understood.
You're awfully compliant today.
随分素直だね今日大丈夫
Are you feeling okay?
どちがいいか
やてみないと分かんねぇし
You never know what works until you try it.
≪月島はたぶん真向から
向かてくる相手に慣れてなくて
Tsukishima probably isn't used to dealing with anyone with a head-on approach, so he's stuck listening.
Okay! We're taking this set!
逃げられないんだよな≫
Yeah!
(田中)ナイスノヤさん
Nice, Noya!
((こちにもやり方があるから
I have my own way of doing things, so I want sets to be consistent.
トスは一定にしてほしい))
(松川)≪えフェイント
A diversion?
Right on!
(成田)しゃ
ブロク真後ろがら空きゾン
It landed in the empty zone right behind the blockers!
He did it!
(木下)やりおた腹立つ
God, he pisses me off!
(縁下)直前まで強打かと思た
(菅原)ナイス
I thought he was gonna smash it at the last second.
Nice!
Tsukishima seems to glow when he gets the ball past an opponent!
月島は相手を出し抜いたとき
イキイキするなぁ
Glow?
イキイキ
(山口)分かりづらいけど
It's hard to tell, but that's how he looks when he's really into the match.
あれは結構ノてる顔
ほぉ
Ooh!
チャンスボル
Here's our chance!
≪またフェイント≫
Another diversion!
ぐ
(岩泉)ナイス渡
Nice, Watari!
It's coming back!
(澤村)返てくるぞ
うまいな１１番
Number eleven is really good at that.
We have another chance!
でも青城ブロク高いしやぱ
真向勝負避けてんじゃない
But isn't he avoiding direct confrontation with Seijou's high blockers?
フェイントなら
ある程度逃げられるもんな
Diversions allow him to avoid dealing with it.
So isn't number eleven actually avoiding the blockers?
(他校生)１１番やぱ
ブロクから逃げてんじゃねぇかな
(東峰)く
ピ
Yes!
おしゃ
う
Nice, Mattsun!
(及川)ナイス松つん
Crap. They took a point right back like it was nothing.
≪くそ
淡々と取り返しやがる≫
Karasuno                   Aoba Jousai
(岩泉)センタ１１番
Number eleven down the center!
Again?
≪またよし今度は拾える
Okay, I can dig it out this time!
(岩泉)ナイスレシブ渡
(及川)オライ
Nice receive, Watari!
I got it!
(金田一)センタ
Center!
(澤村)田中ナイスレシブ
くそ
Tanaka, nice receive!
Shit!
Tread carefully!
慎重に行け
ここは確実に取りたい
Sorry, it's too low! Cover it for me!
This is the one they have to get.
やぱエスに来るか
Will the ace take it?
(月島)
((みんな何かしら考えてる))
Everyone is always thinking.
Number eleven again!
≪また１１番≫
いかん出すぎるな
No! Hold your positions!
う
ピ
(２人)うお
Ooh!
All right!
(西谷)うおしゃ
(田中)むかつくヤツめ
You really piss me off, you bastard!
こんにゃろうめ
(月島)ちょやめてください
You thug!
We were watching so hard for a diversion, our defense pressed too far forward.
フェイントを警戒しすぎて
守備が前のめりになてしまた
That hurts.
I'm sorry!
やられたな
They got us.
Okay, let's get the next one!
ナナフナフスナイス
N... Ni... Nice.
(月島)え
(田中)そこはかむなよ影山
Don't choke on it, Kageyama!
Whoa, Kageyama gave Tsukishima a compliment!
おお影山が月島を褒めた
≪影山も確実に変わてきてる≫
Kageyama is definitely starting to change.
How bad at compliments can you be?!
お前褒めるの
どんだけ下手なんだははは
Karasuno                   Aoba Jousai
(他校生)烏野セトポイントだ
(他校生)マジか
It's set point for Karasuno!
Get out!
One point to go!
あと１点
(山口)もう１点
One more point!
(２人)あ
渡さねぇよ
No, you don't!
Karasuno                   Aoba Jousai
(青城応援団)いいぞいいぞ一
押せ押せ一
(武田)大丈夫１点
It's okay!
One point!
いつもどおりの１点を
取りさえすれば
Get one more point like all the other points,
and you can take this set!
このセトは取れる
Haikyuu !!
(大会委員長)((おめでとう))
Congratulations!
Best Setter Award
Oikawa Tooru
(岩泉･ﾅﾚｰｼｮﾝ)
＜中学３年最後の大会＞
Best Setter Award
Oikawa Tooru
Third year of junior high.
Best Setter Award
Oikawa Tooru
Our last tournament.
((珍しく裏のない笑顔だな))
That's an honest smile for a change.
((俺の笑顔はいつも
ますぐ純粋だよ
My smiles are always pure and innocent!
Saying "pure and innocent" out loud sounds impure.
((ますぐ純粋て響きが
すでに不純だ))
((うれしいに決まてんじゃん
初めてもらたんだし))
Why wouldn't I be happy?
I've never gotten one before!
＜及川徹は
基本的にヘラヘラしている男だ＞
Oikawa Tooru is basically a laughing jackass.
＜でもそいつが
笑わない時期があた＞
But there was a time he couldn't laugh.
＜人より体格に優れていた＞
He had a larger build than most.
＜センスにも恵まれていた＞
He was also naturally gifted.
＜特に中学に上がてからの
上達ぶりは群を抜いていた＞
His improvement was outstanding, especially after junior high.
Miyagi
Prefecture
Junior High
Newbie
Volleyball
Tournament
Miyagi
Prefecture
Junior High
Newbie
Volleyball
Tournament
＜それでも
超えられない壁は常にあた＞
But he was consistently blocked by a brick wall.
＜怪童ウシワカを迎えて
県内最強と言われるようになた
Shiratorizawa Junior High, who became known as the best in the prefecture,
白鳥沢学園中等部＞
had just welcomed "Big Boy" Ushiwaka into its ranks.
(及川)((く
((なんで勝てないんだ
Why can't I beat them?!
＜対戦すれば負けた＞
We played against them and lost.
＜１セトすら取れなかた＞
We didn't even take one set.
＜もと上へ
もと高い舞台へ＞
We wanted to keep going.
To a bigger stage.
But the defeats continued until our third year of junior high.
＜しかし阻まれ続けて中学３年
今度は＞
And that time...
((秋山小出身影山飛雄です))
My name is Kageyama Tobio,
and I went to Akiyama Elementary School.
((バレは小２からです
よろしくお願いします))
I've been playing volleyball since second grade.
It's a pleasure to meet you!
＜背後に天才が現れた＞
A prodigy appeared to take our place.
＜そのセンスは
圧倒的に輝いていた＞
His skill was overwhelmingly obvious.
＜何よりﾎﾞｰﾙに触れていることが
うれしくてしかたない様子と
The way he looked overjoyed to be playing the sport...
それに伴ての
ボルの扱いの慣れ方が
combined with the way he was used to handling a ball was far above the rest.
ほかとは段違いだた＞
(監督)((基本
いろんなポジシｮンはやらせるが
Basically, he can do all kinds of positions, but he'll eventually be a setter.
ゆくゆくはセタだな))
(コチ)((ええ))
Yes.
＜及川はそれまで以上に
練習に打ち込むようになた＞
After that, Oikawa started to practice even harder than before.
((オバワクだぞ
昨日も監督に注意されたろうが
You're working too hard!
Coach warned you about that just yesterday!
(岩泉)((うらぁケガしたら
元も子もねぇんだボケ
It's all for nothing if you get injured, moron!
((おら終わりだ
ストレチ
C'mon, you're done! Stretch!
＜ひたすら
焦ている様子だた＞
He was completely losing his cool.
＜その焦りは練習試合で
今までにありえない回数の
His lack of composure showed in a practice match in the form of several unimaginable setting mistakes.
コンビミスとなて現れた
そして＞
And then...
((はぁはぁ
(監督)((影山入てみろ))
((はい))
Kageyama, get in there.
Yes, sir!
(副審)((オケです))
Okay.
(岩泉)((前前
((オライ
Forward!
I've got it!
Nice cover!
(部員)((ナイスカバ
(岩泉)((ナイスキ
Nice spike!
(部員)((ナイサ
((ピ
Give us a good serve!
((はぁはぁはぁ))
((及川さん))
((あ
Oikawa?
((サブ教えてください))
Please teach me how to serve.
(及川)≪来るな
Get away from me.
来るな
≪こちに来るな
Don't come near me!
Get a grip, you moron!
((落ち着けこのボゲ
(及川)((ごめん))
(岩泉)((影山
I'm sorry.
Kageyama, I'm sorry, but we're done for the day.
悪いけど今日は終わりだ))
((あはい))
Um, sure.
(岩泉)((今日の交代はおめぇの頭を
冷やすためだろうがよ
We swapped you out today to give you the chance to get it together.
ちょとは余裕持て))
((はく
Give yourself some credit!
How can I possibly give myself credit if I'm not good enough to beat Shiratorizawa?!
((今の俺じゃ
白鳥沢に勝てないのに
余裕なんかあるわけない
俺は勝て全国に行きたいんだ
I want to win and go to nationals!
((勝つために俺はもと
To win, I have to work harder!
It's all "me, me, me"! Just shut up!
(岩泉)
((｢俺が俺が｣てうるせぇ
((てめぇ一人で
戦てるつもりか
Do you think you're playing all by yourself?!
That's not even funny, moron!
((冗談じゃねぇぞボゲェ
てめぇの出来が
If you believe that your performance equals team performance, I'm gonna belt you one!
イコルチムの出来だなんて
思い上がてるなら
ぶん殴るぞ
((もう殴てるよ))
You already did.
((１対１で
ウシワカに勝てるヤツなんか
No one in our team can take on Ushiwaka one on one!
うちにはいねぇよけど
But there are six people on a volleyball court!
バレはコトに６人だべや
((相手が天才１年だろうが
ウシワカだろうが
I don't care if we're against a
first-year prodigy or Ushiwaka!
６人で強い方が強いんだろうが
ボゲが
The team with the best six players is obviously the best, moron!
(及川)((６人で強い方が強い
ふふふ
The team with the best six players is the best?
(岩泉)((あすまん
強く頭突きしすぎたか
I'm sorry. Did I headbutt you too hard?
(及川)((はぁうん
Yeah.
It's like, I can't even describe this.
なんかなんだろうなこれ))
((俄然無敵な気分
I just suddenly feel invincible.
ていうか岩ちゃん
悪口ボゲしか言えないの
Wait, Iwa. Is "moron" the only bad name you can call me?
You wanna bleed from your other nostril too?
(岩泉)
((右からも鼻血出してやろうか))
(及川)
((ナイスコスもう一本
Nice location!
One more point!
(コチ)((なんというか及川は
I'm surprised. Oikawa looks like he's over it.
吹切れたように見えますね))
(監督)((うむ))
Yes.
Oikawa, please teach me how to toss the ball up before a serve.
((及川さんサブトスのコツを
((嫌だねバカバカ
I don't think so, you dum-dum!
Oikawa, stop messing with the first-year.
(岩泉)((及川１年に絡むんじゃねぇ))
((べぇだ
(岩泉)＜中学最後の大会
In our last tournament in junior high against Shiratorizawa,
Kitagawa First                Shiratorizawa
対白鳥沢中等部＞
＜初めて１セトを取た＞
we won our very first set.
＜結果は白鳥沢に次いで２位＞
In the end, we took second place to Shiratorizawa.
Best Setter Award
Oikawa Tooru
＜及川は
ベストセタ賞を獲得した＞
Best Setter Award
Oikawa Tooru
Oikawa earned the best setter award.
Best Setter Award
Oikawa Tooru
This award is the proof that our spikers did their very best.
(及川)
((この賞はうちのスパイカが
いちばん
力を発揮してたて証拠だ))
Doesn't that mean Ushiwaka is even better?
(岩泉)((それでも
ウシワカは更にその上かよ
くそ))
(及川)((高校行たら
Dammit.
When I get to high school...
今度こそ
白鳥沢へこましてやる))
I'm gonna humiliate Shiratorizawa instead!
((当然だ))
That's a given!
And then there's you, Tobio!
(及川)((そして飛雄ちゃん
((え
((お前がこの先
どう進むのか知らないけど
I don't know where you'll move on to next,
but when I do play against you, prepare to get creamed!
いつか戦うときは
ぶ潰してやるから覚悟してなよ))
(岩泉)((決めゼリフは
はなかんでから言えよ))
Big talk for someone who needs to wipe his nose.
((ティシュ使いますか
(及川)((うるさい
Would you like a tissue?
Shut up!
Go for it! Go, go, go, go, Seijou!
(部員)行け
行け行け行け行け青城
(青城応援団)行け
Karasuno                      Aoba Jousai
(澤村)さ来い
(岩泉)サ
Okay, bring it!
Let's do it!
Give us a good one!
(花巻)ナイサ
ここで及川君のサブ
Now it's Oikawa's turn to serve.
(岩泉)お前がへこましたい相手
その２が目の前だ
You're facing the guy who's second on your humiliation list!
思い切りでいいぞ
Give it all you've got.
分かてるよ
ピ
I know.
Olé!
Nishinoya!
西谷
上がた
あ
It's up!
But it's heading right back to Seijou!
けど直接青城側に返ちまう
≪このサブミスたら
セト落とすのに
One mistake and that serve could've cost them the set! What a serve!
なんつうサブだ
すげぇこいつ≫
This dude is amazing!
チャンスボル
Here's our chance!
≪レシブは
きれいにセタに返た≫
The receive neatly came back to the setter.
It has a high rate of success
≪決定率が高いのは
センタからの速攻≫
due to fast attacks from the center!
≪だろうたぶん
俺だたらそうする≫
That must be it.
That's what I would do.
≪でも追い込まれたこの場面
及川さんは
Now that his back is against the wall...
≪岩泉さんに上げる
Oikawa will set it to Iwaizumi!
ピ
(４人)うおしゃ
All right!
Karasuno                       Aoba Jousai
(他校生)マジか
(他校生)烏野がセト取り返した
For real?
Karasuno took back a set.
くそがすまん
(花巻)ドンマイ
That piece of shit! I'm sorry!
Shake it off.
(及川)はははは
何笑てんだぶん殴るぞ
Why are you laughing?!
I'll clobber you!
Stop saying you're going to punch me, Iwa.
(及川)すぐ殴るて言うの
やめなよ岩ちゃん
Relax.
(岩泉)安心しろ
おめぇにしか言わねぇし殴んねぇよ
You're the only one I threaten, and I won't hit you!
(及川)今のはｾﾝﾀｰからの速攻が
ベタな攻撃だた
That last fast attack from the center was one of our better attacks.
あ
(及川)でもおそらく飛雄は今
Huh?
I think Tobio must've predicted
Good boy! Good boy!
俺がレフトに上げると読んでいた
この意味分かる
that I would set it to the left.
Do you understand what this means?
今までみたいに
機械的に考えるだけじゃなく
He wasn't thinking mechanically like he's always done.
終盤こちの劣勢ていう状況
He saw that we were on the back foot toward the end...
岩ちゃんと俺の超絶信頼関係
(岩泉)あてたまるかそんなもの
along with our relationship of absolute mutual trust.
We have no such thing.
(及川)そういう
総合的な判断をしてきたてこと
Which means he made a comprehensive judgment call.
(及川)あの爽やか君は
What did Mr. Pleasant over there teach Tobio?
飛雄に何を教えた
ただの独裁の王様が
A king who's nothing but a dictator is trying to become a decent king.
まともな王様に
なろうとしている
なんだこれ
What is this?
How can I feel this way while I feel so incredibly irritated?!
すごいムシャクシャしてんのに
この感じ
ふ
は
Now!
早く早くやろう
I want to play the last set now!
ファイナルセト
Next Episode Preview
We've reached the last set.
What can I say? It really isn't like me to get so worked up.
(岩泉)フｧイナルセｯトまで来たな
(及川)いや
It's really unusual.
ガラにもなく熱くなちゃた
(岩泉)珍しいじゃねぇか
I have my ice queen image to maintain!
Maintain your volleyball image!
(及川)クルビュティが
売りなのにね
Next time on Haikyuu!!:
(岩泉)バレを売りにしろよ
Episode Twenty-three:
The Play to Shift the Momentum
"The Play to Shift the Momentum."